<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://www.duncbell.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://www.duncbell.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-06-26T20:04:09+00:00</updated><id>http://www.duncbell.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">duncbell.com</title><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title type="html">Storm</title><link href="http://www.duncbell.com/2025/01/01/Storm.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Storm" /><published>2025-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://www.duncbell.com/2025/01/01/Storm</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.duncbell.com/2025/01/01/Storm.html"><![CDATA[<p>In the afternoon we walk down to the sea. We get to the shore, turn onto the path directly into the wind, spray blowing into our faces, and change our minds almost immediately. We’ll walk downwind instead. Within a couple of minutes there is more indecision over the route and we revert to our original plan to see the waves blown up by the gale. Now we’re taking the brunt of the wind into our shoulders; and enjoying it. Joking of “feeling alive”, but we do. A shields his face from the wind and we pull the hood of the buggy right down over him. He’s quite happy in there, looking up through the vent.</p>

<p>We follow the sound of a deep whistling “vrrrrrm” wind  noise, speculating as to its source; turning torso (“how annoying to live there with that”), some old ship parts installed at the top of a bank, street furniture… As we approach Västra Hamnen we discover it’s the sound of the gale blowing through the rigging of boats in the small harbour, there.</p>

<p>Later, between buildings, the wind makes it difficult to walk. We let Alve out to enjoy the force of it. He seems to like the power assist when running downwind.</p>

<p>We’re in the supermarket dressed for the mountains. Or the high seas.</p>

<p>I’m deeper into <em>Wish I was here</em>. Reading his thoughts on writing, particularly weird writing or writing weird, take me back to reading <em>The sunken land begins to rise again</em>. Always so close to some sort of meaning but never getting there. So much that is metaphor, but for what purpose? A podcast I listened to mentions a medium which prompts a connection to <em>Back to black</em>. Ghosts, edge-lands, weirdness adjacent to the ordinary, the weirdness of the ordinary.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the afternoon we walk down to the sea. We get to the shore, turn onto the path directly into the wind, spray blowing into our faces, and change our minds almost immediately. We’ll walk downwind instead. Within a couple of minutes there is more indecision over the route and we revert to our original plan to see the waves blown up by the gale. Now we’re taking the brunt of the wind into our shoulders; and enjoying it. Joking of “feeling alive”, but we do. A shields his face from the wind and we pull the hood of the buggy right down over him. He’s quite happy in there, looking up through the vent.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Mellandagarna</title><link href="http://www.duncbell.com/2024/12/27/Mellandagarna.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mellandagarna" /><published>2024-12-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-12-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://www.duncbell.com/2024/12/27/Mellandagarna</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.duncbell.com/2024/12/27/Mellandagarna.html"><![CDATA[<p>We took A to Saluhallen to eat falafel and chips. He was an expert dipper; definitely not his first time. It was fun to watch him dip into the mustard instead of the ketchup. The strength of the flavour caught him by surprise. He still seemed under the weather but enjoyed climbing on the crazy bear, goose, boar, snake, deer statue in the park.</p>

<p>Finished <em>Headshot</em> by Rita Bullwinkel. I’m not good at articulating what I like in a book but this really hooked me.</p>

<p>I picked up <em>Wish I was here</em> by MJ Harrison, again after finishing Headshot. Then read a few of his blog entries before bed time. I love his writing. I think <em>Climbers</em> is such a fantastic novel. <em>Light</em> I found quite hard work. His social media and blogging is great.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We took A to Saluhallen to eat falafel and chips. He was an expert dipper; definitely not his first time. It was fun to watch him dip into the mustard instead of the ketchup. The strength of the flavour caught him by surprise. He still seemed under the weather but enjoyed climbing on the crazy bear, goose, boar, snake, deer statue in the park.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">“Problem Statements”</title><link href="http://www.duncbell.com/2024/10/23/problem-statements.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="“Problem Statements”" /><published>2024-10-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://www.duncbell.com/2024/10/23/problem-statements</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.duncbell.com/2024/10/23/problem-statements.html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="the-problem-statement-canvas">The Problem Statement Canvas</h1>

<blockquote>
  <p>A problem well stated is a problem half solved - Charles Kettering</p>
</blockquote>

<p>I first encountered the Problem Statement Canvas while working in government, probably in around 2016. It was presented to our team by colleagues in a strategy unit somewhere within the department. I think the idea came from somewhere in the Cabinet Office. I’ve used them ever since. For all manner of problems, mainly professional but occasionally personal.</p>

<p><a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1wmFzOrHX0M_BkRBBQF0PKnc56XZYmeiM/edit?usp=sharing&amp;ouid=110089811960815598990&amp;rtpof=true&amp;sd=true">Problem Statement Canvas</a></p>

<p>The canvas is a series of prompts that help you understand the current conditions of a piece of work or situation. The method I was taught was that you should</p>
<ul>
  <li>start with the context box;</li>
  <li>then work through all the remaining, lower, boxes;</li>
  <li>these should all be filled with short bullet pointed lists, or similar;</li>
  <li>once you have completed the lower boxes, return to the top of the canvas and attempt to write a single sentence problem statement in the “Basic problem to be solved” box. This statement should follow the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SMART_criteria">SMART</a> format.</li>
</ul>

<p>It’s often very difficult to distill all of the information to a single sentence problem statement. The advice I was given from the beginning was to just try and write something, anything. Then re-write it. And again, if necessary. Until you are happy that your statement properly describes the problem you face.</p>

<p>The canvas can be used at any time, in any phase of a piece of work. But they are particularly helpful when starting on a new piece of work. As a user researcher I’ve used them as the pre-cursor to a research plan. Recently, as a product manger, I’ve written them as the start point to a couple of new initiatives we’re focusing on this quarter.</p>

<ul>
  <li>Primarily, I use the canvas to prompt myself to think systematically and thoroughly about a problem. The process is akin to a convergent-divergent diamond, you gather data then synthesise it into a simple statement.</li>
  <li>They are also a helpful way of gaining consensus on what you are working on within a small group of key people.</li>
  <li>Finally, they are easy to share, so are handy for communicating to a wider group.</li>
</ul>

<p>The version I linked to above is a word doc. My favourite version is a Figma design file with a simple auto layout that re-scales nicely. But I know the canvas so well now that I don’t really need a template; the most recent one was just bulleted lists under a series of headers written on the notes app on my phone.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Problem Statement Canvas]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Posting from mobile</title><link href="http://www.duncbell.com/2024/10/12/Posting-from-mobile.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Posting from mobile" /><published>2024-10-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://www.duncbell.com/2024/10/12/Posting-from-mobile</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.duncbell.com/2024/10/12/Posting-from-mobile.html"><![CDATA[<p>I’m experimenting with posting from mobile using Bear as my markdown editor, then copy-pasting to GitHub. It’s a bit fiddly but I think it will work quite well.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’m experimenting with posting from mobile using Bear as my markdown editor, then copy-pasting to GitHub. It’s a bit fiddly but I think it will work quite well.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Trying To Post With Jekyll</title><link href="http://www.duncbell.com/2024/10/11/Trying-to-post-with-jekyll.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Trying To Post With Jekyll" /><published>2024-10-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://www.duncbell.com/2024/10/11/Trying-to-post-with-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.duncbell.com/2024/10/11/Trying-to-post-with-jekyll.html"><![CDATA[<p>I’ve been trying to get Jekyll to work but it’s playing up.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’ve been trying to get Jekyll to work but it’s playing up.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Getting (re-)started</title><link href="http://www.duncbell.com/2024/10/10/Getting-restarted.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Getting (re-)started" /><published>2024-10-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://www.duncbell.com/2024/10/10/Getting-restarted</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.duncbell.com/2024/10/10/Getting-restarted.html"><![CDATA[<p>I finally decided to re-claim my own space on the web. This time I wanted something a bit easier to maintain - the previous incarnation was a wordpress - and a lot cheaper - I got stung with some crazy high renewal fees with my last web hosts. After About 20 minutes of Chat GPT and Reddit research I decided to host on github, and re-register my domain from a much cheaper source (I also chose to register for three years, so perhaps this version will live a bit longer than the, now disappeared, portfolio one).
My aim is to have something a bit more reflective of me. Not just a professional page. Precisely what that means, I don’t know. But I will re-write at least one post that I lost and add a few things that I’ve been working with recently.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I finally decided to re-claim my own space on the web. This time I wanted something a bit easier to maintain - the previous incarnation was a wordpress - and a lot cheaper - I got stung with some crazy high renewal fees with my last web hosts. After About 20 minutes of Chat GPT and Reddit research I decided to host on github, and re-register my domain from a much cheaper source (I also chose to register for three years, so perhaps this version will live a bit longer than the, now disappeared, portfolio one). My aim is to have something a bit more reflective of me. Not just a professional page. Precisely what that means, I don’t know. But I will re-write at least one post that I lost and add a few things that I’ve been working with recently.]]></summary></entry></feed>